good evening ladies and gentlemen a very
warm welcome to ICI Lumar General
Insurance company limited's Q2 and H1 FY
2025 earnings conference
call from the senior management team we
have with us today Mr sanjie mantri MD
and CEO of the company Mr gopal
balachandran
CFO Mr Girish nyak Chief technology and
health underwriting and claims Mr sandip
gadia Chief corporate solutions group
and Mr Anand singi Chief retail and
government
business please note that any statements
or comments made in today's call that
may look like forward-looking statements
are based on information presently
available to the management and do not
constitute an indication of any future
performance as future involves risks and
uncertainties which could cause results
to differ materially from the current
views being expressed
as a reminder all participant lines will
be in the listen only mode there will be
an opportunity for you to ask questions
after the presentation
concludes should you need assistance
during this conference please signal the
operator by pressing star and then zero
on your Touchstone
phone I now hand the conference over to
Mr sanjie mantri MD and CEO ICI lombar
General Insurance Limited thank you and
over to you sir thank
you good evening to each one of you
thank you for joining the earning
conference call of icsl Omar General
Insurance Company Limited for quarter 2
nh1 Financial year
2025 let me give you a brief overview of
the industry Trends and developments
that we have witnessed in the ensuing
months post this our CFO Mr gopal
balachandran will share the financial
performance of the company for the
quarter and a half year ended September
30th 2024
during the quarter 1
2025 India's real GDP grew by 6.7%
primly driven by private consumption
moving into the Q2 of financial year
2025 the government expenditure started
witnessing an uptake GST collections
continue to remain steady and Q for Q2
and the direct tax collections are
growing at a decent pace this may
provide much needed support to retail
spending in the upcoming festive season
further a normal Monsoon may help Drive
rural demand in coming months
nevertheless the current situation in
West Asia region and a substantial
increase in crude prices remains a major
risk for the overall economic
growth speaking of General Insurance
performance the industry delivered a
gdpi growth of 7% for H1 of financial
year 2025 over H1 of financial year
2024 impacted by quarter to financial
2025 growth of
2% however excluding crop and massale
segments the the industry registered
growth at 10.9% for H1 of 2025 and 6.9%
for quarter 2 Financial year
2025 now talking about the Auto industry
growth for the quarter was muted as
reported by CM private car with higher
base degre at
1.8% two wheelers GRE at
12.6% and CV degre at
3.2% this this entails approximately 2.1
million private cars 10.2 million to
wheelers and8 million CVS being sold in
H1 of 2025 further the retail numbers as
reported by F has also seen degrowth for
private car at 5.1% two wheer growth at
4.7% and CV growth remained muted at
1.1% for quarter 2 Financial year
2025 the health segment doing the
quarter continue to deliver double digit
growth largely driven by retail business
registering growth of 17.7%
the growth in the group business was
moderated due to fing pressure and the
health business was impacted due to
relatively muted disbursement by
financial
institutions the commercial line segment
during the quarter was a mixed bag with
industry growth at 2% while fire segment
degw at 10.7% on account of pricing
pressure however government spend on
infrastructure development and
acceleration in private sector
investment has spurred Positive Growth
especially in segments such as
engineering liability and
Marine the regulatory environment
continues to focus on policy holders
interest while fostering Innovation
competition and sustainable growth for
the industry thereby reinforcing the
Authority's vision of insurance for all
by
2047 overall for the medium to long term
we remain positive that The General
insurance industry will continue to grow
given the favorable regulatory changes
low penetration and Rising disposable
income now speaking of the underwriting
performance of the industry the combine
ratio for the industry remain at 113.9
for quarter 1 Financial year 2025 as
against 11 13.5% for quarter 1 Financial
year
2024 for the motor business the
industry's combined ratio wors to
25.6% in quarter 1 Financial year
2025 from
121% in quarter 1 2024 which can be
largely attributed to the increase in
loss ratios
now let me update you on performance of
key business segments for us the
company's gdpi for quarter 2 Financial
year 2025 grew by 10.4% as compared to
the industry growth of
2% excluding crop and mass the company
grew by 99.4% as compared to the
industry growth of
6.9% in the commercial line segment we
grew at 1.2% as against industry growth
of
2% we continue to maintain leaders ship
position in engineering liability and
Marine cargo segment however in the fire
segment we remain Vigilant in terms of
risk selection while maintaining a
market
share in motor segment during the
quarter we registered a growth of 16.1%
as against the industry growth of
6.2% the overall growth in motor segment
during the quarter was AED by growth in
Old
business we continue to maintain the
market share leadership with robust
capabilities across distribution and
writing claims servicing and actal
practices during the quarter we
sustained a balanced portfolio with a
mix of Private Car two wheer and CV at 5
54.4% 24.6% and 21%
respectively our preferred partner
Network enabled us to survey 72.8% of
our non OEM claims in quarter 2 of 2025
up from 63.4% in quarter to a financial
year
2024 the Health segment grew at 12.3% in
quarter 2 Financial year 2025 led by
retail Health we registered a growth of
41.4% in quarter to 2025 as against
industry growth of 17.7% in the retail
Health segment our growth in quarter 2
was supported by our recently launched
product elevate a market share for
retail Health segment has now reach 3.5%
in quarter to a financial year
2025 in the group health employer
employee segment we look we took a
cautious approach due to increased
competitive intensity cons consequently
we grew by 1% in quarter 2 Financial
year 2025 as compared to growth of 34.6%
in quarter one of financial year
2025 during the quarter our bank of
Business deew by 2.6% due to lower
credit disbursement growth in our key
relationship
Partners within this icsa group dis
distribution grew by 19 6% for quarter
to a financial year 2025 due to a
continued strategic focus on Branch
Banking business we continue to
strengthen our digital business during
the quarter our customer facing digital
business grew by
14.7% constituting 6.3% of our overall
gdpi our investments in new customer
acquisition strategy through website led
to a growth in fresh business of motor
and health segment by 45.9% in quarter
to financial year 2025
our onetop solution for all insurance
and wellness needs the IL take care app
has surpassed 11.6 million user
downloads F date registering a premium
of 55 5 56.8 million for the
quarter as discussed in a previous call
we continue to harness synergies through
one Al one team under this one one of
our initiatives one Al One Call Center
we have Consolidated multiple call
centers into three specialized teams
fresh acquisition renewals and servicing
to drive Improvement in operational
efficiencies and the overall customer
experience additionally our investment
in CRM technology and AI tools have
further increased productivity by high
team and improved customer service
particularly in retail health and motor
segments in conclusion we continue to
strengthen a multi-product
multi-distribution strategy led by a
focus on product Innovation data
analytics and digital enhancements the
these initiatives coupled with the
spirit of one one team position as well
to capitalize on future opportunities
and drive profitable growth I will now
request gopal to take you through the
financial numbers for the Recently
concluded quarter and half year thanks
aiv and uh good evening to each one of
you I will now give you a brief overview
of the financial performance of the
recently concluded quarter and half
years we have uploaded the results
results presentation on our website you
can access it as we walk you through the
performance numbers gross direct premium
income of the company was at rupees
144.5 billion in H1 fi25 as gained R
24.72 billion in H1 FY 24 a growth of
15.5% against the industry growth of 7%
excluding crop and Mass health gdpi
growth of the company was at 15% which
was higher than the industry growth of
10.9% in H1
fy2 gdpi was at r 67.2 1 billion in Q2
fi25 as against R 6.86 billion in Q2 fi
24 a growth of
10.4% this again was higher than the
industry growth of 2% excluding crop and
mass sales gdpi growth of the company
was at
99.4% which was higher than the industry
growth of 6.9% in quarter to fi25 our
gdpi growth during the quarter was
mainly driven by preferred lines of
businesses on the retail side of the
business gdpi of the motor segment was
at R 24.8 billion in Q2
fi25 as against R 2.38 billion in Q2 fi
24 registering a growth of
16.1% the advanced premium number was R
35.13 billion as at September 30 2024 as
against rupes 34.56 billion as at June
2024 gdpi of the health segment was at
rupes 15.29 billion in Q2 F525 as
against r
13.625 f524 again registering a growth
of
12.3% our agents which includes the
point of sale distribution count was
13368 as on September 30 2024 up from
13121 as at June 30 2024 the overall GDP
of our commercial line segment grew by
1.2% at rupes
14.93% during the quarter the industry
witnessed multiple catastrophic events
namely floods in and Andra telingana
North India Gujarat etc etc impacting
our combined isues which was 103.2 for
H1 fi25 as against
103.8 for H1
f524 excluding this impact of cat losses
which was rupes .94 billion in H1 fy2
and r83 billion in H1 f24 the combined
ratios were
102.2 and 10 12.7% respectively combined
ratio was 10 14.5% in Q2 fi25 as against
103.9 in Q2 fi 24 again excluding the
impact of cat losses primarily we had
the cat losses in Q2 this year which was
again rupes .94 billion and r48 billion
in Q2 fi 24 the combined ratio was 2.6%
and 10 2.8% respectively our investment
assets during the quarter Rose to rupees
55.57 billion as at September 30 2024 up
from rupes 51.4 billion as at June 30
2024 our investment leverage net of
borrowings was 3.91 times as at
September 13 2024 as againsted 4.14
times as at June 30
2024 investment income was at r 22.52%
ion in H1 fi25 as against 18 billion in
H1
f524 on a quarterly basis investment
income was at R 11.24 billion in Q2 F525
as against R 9.56 billion in Q2
f524 our capital gains net of impairment
on investment assets stood at R 5.21
billion in H1 fi25 as against rupes 2.82
billion in H1 f24 capital gains net of
impairment investment assets for the
quarter to fi25 St rupes 2.37 billion as
compared to rupes 1.65 billion in Q2
fi4 our profit before tax grew by 31.9%
at R 16.93 billion in H1 fi25 as against
R 12.84 billion in H1 f524 whereas PBT
grew by 20.3% at rupes 9.19 billion in
Q2 fi25 as against rupes 7.64 billion in
Q2
f524 consequently profit after tax grew
by 31.7% at r 12.74% in H1
fi25 as againsted R 9.68 billion in H1
f524 profit after tax again grew by
20.2% for this quarter to fi25 at 6.94
billion rupees up from rupees 5.77
billion in Q to fi 24 the return on
average Equity was 20.3% in H1 fi25 as
against 18% in H1 f24 the return on
average equity for Q2 fi25 was
21.8% as against 21.1% in q to f24
solvency ratio was healthy at 2.65 times
as at September 13 2024 as a ganged 2.56
times as at June 30 2024 continued to be
higher than the minimum regulatory
requirement of 1.5 times the board of
directors of the company has declared an
interim dividend of rupees 5.5 per share
for H1 fi25 as against rupes 5 per share
which was for H1
f24 as I conclude I would like to
reaffirm that we continue to stay
focused on driving sustainable value
creation and profitable growth while
protecting the interest of policy
holders at all times I would like to
thank you all for attending this
earnings call and we will now be happy
to take any questions that you have
thank
you thank you very much we will now
begin the question and answer session
anyone who wishes to ask a question may
press star and one on the touchdown
telephone if you wish to withdraw
yourself from the question Q you may
press star and two
participants are requested to please use
handsets while asking a question ladies
and gentlemen we will wait for a moment
while the question que
assembled the first question is from the
line of Shrea Shivani from clsa please
go ahead
uh thank you for the opportunity uh I
have two questions uh first is on the
net commission rate for the quarter it
seems like it's slightly elevated when I
compare it to the second quarter of last
year could it be uh because of uh higher
sales in the retail Health segment are
we have we changed our commission
structure in that product or is it just
because the product mix has shifted more
towards that place uh that segment uh
that's the first question and second uh
sir uh majority of the rise uh in the in
the combined ratio in this quarter has
been because of the catastrophic losses
uh so will we still hold on to our
guidance of being able to touch 101.5
the as a closing combined ratio in 4 q25
uh given that majority from catastrophe
and in case we don't see any more sge
and cycling so uh just the guidance
around that thank you yeah I think gopal
will answer the first one and then I'll
talk about the guidance part yeah so I
think uh you're absolutely right I think
uh so far as a net commission ratio
numbers are concerned it's obviously a
function of uh the mix of business that
you underwrite and uh as you would have
seen I think our approach to writing
risk as what we put out also as a part
of the open opening transcript was to
drive profitable growth and therefore in
that context when you look at the mix of
business largely what we have been able
to drive is uh profitable businesses in
motor and uh the retail Health segment
in specific spefic and relative to that
I think our growth in let's say the
group health SL commercial lines have
been relatively uh muted and that's
clearly a factor that has contributed to
let's say the change in the net
commission ratio and given the fact that
we have also been a bit cautious on the
commercial line there is also some bit
of impact in so far as uh reinsurance
commissions are concerned so because the
ratio is on a net commission basis so
therefore it is a factor of both change
in business
as well as let's say our approach to
being a bit cautious on the commercial
line side commercial line side which is
what has contributed to the net
commission numbers to your point on have
we changed anything in so far as uh
commission structures are concerned I
think the short answer is uh I think we
keep looking for Market opportunities in
terms of how we want to ride businesses
but at an aggregate level I think what
we stand committed is to kind of make
sure that from an experence of
management standpoint which includes
both Commission plus operating expenses
both of that put together as a company
we stand committed to make sure that we
well within the limit of 30% at an
aggregate level San yeah so overall
you're right the Cat event uh in the
quarter 2 has impacted the loss ratio by
1.9% and thereabouts uh otherwise
overall the command issue of the company
if net of Cat event it looked at that's
shown an improvement uh uh in terms of
the guidance at things stand uh we have
no reason to change the guidance at this
point of time uh we very keenly will
look at the industry numbers also as
they come out on the quarter 2 and the
H1 pnl uh I spoke about uh in my own uh
script which I said that the quarter one
number for the industry has come out uh
relatively status quo while we used to
have a w Improvement uh uh last year but
that also has come on account of
elevated loss ratio and little bit of
impact on the account of uh expenses uh
we stay committed we have no reason to
at this point of time deviate from it uh
we do look at the intensity and the
landscape that you see in the commentary
overall as to what's happening on the
commercial line of business uh we grew
ghr business at almost 31% and
thereabouts uh we end the quarter two
again you look at the numbers we have
gone down and we clearly do understand
that uh uh these are all changes the
fire business has uh had gone through a
bit of a concern conern in terms of
where the discounting has uh increased
again uh We've abstained from any wild
participation and still we've been able
to maintain the market share on uh on
each of these uh business lines so yes
we stay committed to that but we
continue to watch the market scenario I
think just to only add to that sh I
think what we would say is uh in fact uh
we will start seeing this impact felt
from an overall Market as well um and if
you would have seen in general given our
ability to risk select portfolios our
exposure from some of these cat events
have been relatively lower compared to
the Natural market share that we have
had as a company and hence a large part
of this change consequent to the cat
losses will also be reflected from a
market perspective at the time of the
reinsurance renewals that will start
happening from the next year so in fact
the real impact is something that you
will start seeing from an industry
standpoint at the time of the
reinsurance renewals which will kick in
for next year
got it understood so you're saying your
reinsure your catastrophe reinsurance
will be priced uh worth off for us for
the industry going ahead right because
of the number these are events that are
playing out right so honestly if you ask
us could we have anticipated let's say
about four events coming and eating us
at an industry level in one quarter the
short answer is no and therefore and
with let's say wavering weather patterns
that you're seeing uh across periods
honestly I think one will have to kind
of wait and see how this develops and
then maybe as things move forward we
will be able to start giving you better
Insight yeah got it very useful thank
you so much and all the best thank you
thank you ladies and gentlemen we
request you to please restrict your
questions to two questions per
participant you may rejoin the queue for
followup
questions we have the next question from
the line of Praise Jen from motilal
oswal please go
ahead yeah hi good evening everyone uh
just a question this questions on the
motor segment so in our last quarter you
had mentioned about the growth in new
versus old so it will be great if you
could share a similar trajectory for H1
and just an extension to that whether
you know the the growth in the in the
renewal or the older business not the
new vehicle has been stronger what are
the drivers for the same that you have
been kind of been able to get more more
growth there
and second question would be on the
motor Outlook again uh you mentioned in
the opening remarks that the growth has
been slowing down in terms of number of
vehicles and so do you see and whatever
the Outlook that we hearing is that it's
Outlook is also going to be muted in the
second half even for first season the
demand Outlook is not expected to be
great so what kind of growth trajectory
should we anticipate for the motor
segment especially in the H2 yeah those
would be my
question the first PR on the first one I
think uh uh if you recollect what we had
said in quarter 1 when the aggregate
growth in motor for us was about 26% at
that point of time we had said the
growth in new was about 16 and the
growth in renewal was roughly about
33% U and given what we had talked about
as a part of this opening transcript in
terms of as you rightly indicated new
being relatively muted uh pretty much on
similar lines I think if you ask us for
Quarter Two the growth in New has been
flattish uh and a large part of the
growth of that 16% that we spoke about
has been significantly aided by growth
in the rual book or let's say the old
book which has grown at almost about 26%
uh so that's a split this is
specifically in the context of quarter 2
uh Vis what we had seen in uh q1 uh to
your point on what's driving let's say
some of this uh growth I think uh as a
company I think we have always been kind
of looking at uh which we have spoken
about even in earlier calls I think
while we stay invested in obviously
leveraging our relative strength on U
OEM dealership Partnerships but at the
same time we have also been
significantly investing on our agency SL
uh other distributions as well and um in
that context our our strength on
distribution service use of Technology
all of that is what is kind of
significantly aiding the growth in the
renewal book plus equally if you
recollect what we also talked about uh
was also to kind of significantly move
into let's say a one one call center
initiative under which we would we
wanted to kind of which is also what we
put out as a part of the opening
transcript to kind of also have a
significant Focus as one of the streams
in so far as retentions are concerned
and that is also in uh in a big way is
aiding the growth in the uh old
book so on the second point on the motor
Outlook you're right uh the uh the
overall numbers that has come out uh for
the industry has been muted and there's
nothing new that we are talking about it
it's all over every possible you know uh
Channel as to where the industry is uh
but I was also highlight one fact that
on private car in particular which
contributes more than 50% of our uh
practice as far as motor is concerned uh
it's on a very high base we've had a
very secular run on private car as an
industry uh almost you know when the co
was still there and then it kind of
continued for a while so on a very high
base if it is flattish also it does not
overly concerns us uh yes and two
wheeler has uh shown better numbers but
two wheer also had recovered only 8 85%
of preo levels while private car has
moved in the zone of 130 to 140% of what
it was preo Peak uh commercial vehicle
mixed bag but uh which can be a proxy in
many ways to the industrial activ
which takes place we do believe it can
pick up in quarter end of quarter three
or maybe you know by quarter 4 so
overall yes we are expecting a single
digit growth uh in H2 but that itself
should suffice and this also is a
backdrop that uh as an industry we've
had not much of a TP hike uh for almost
uh you know last three years if I may
say so it's a it's a combined Factor uh
which stays but we stay committed to
harness what works for us so there is uh
we we are excited with H2 also and the
festive season has just got started food
Falls have been high uh the sales
numbers are still building up probably
we'll have a much better sense how the
festive season goes by uh by November
mid and there about once the Diwali part
is
over just a clarification on this uh you
mentioned the single digit growth that
you expecting a is for vehicle sales or
or is it for the premium growth of the
motor segment for General Insurance
indust I'm I'm I'm talking about the
premium the vehicle sale is what I'm
referring to vehicle sale yeah yeah yeah
yeah yeah yeah all right thank you thank
you thank
you the next question is from the line
of mukar ladha from Nama wealth
management limited please go ahead hi uh
good evening sir uh so so um first I
think in your opening remarks you
mentioned that on the motor segment in
industry combined uh ratios have
worsened now um in this backdrop I think
H1 your performance has been very good
and uh and you know do you think that
this will be
sustainable
um given you know industry loss ratios
are wors and so uh how how do you think
uh you know this can uh plan out do you
think uh
um it the comparative intensity is is
good higher or uh yeah so that's that's
question number
one
hello okay you want to put your second
question if you have I should answer
this no and second s uh you know last
year uh we were sort of discussing that
uh IID a lot of your competition is sort
of above the 30% uh um you know expense
and commission ratio so and is not in
compliance of the Norms so uh is IID
looking to do something about it what is
the c process of there uh because um you
know that may help in getting industry
combined ratios under check and and we
can benefit in that scenario yeah so so
fair I think so I'll uh answer both of
them uh on the core side when we spoke
about motor the core for the industry
has moved from 121 to
12.6 so clearly it's wor ear uh when you
look at the loss ratio on that the
industry had in quarter one last year
loss ratio of 84.5 it gone to
87.6 and there's an increase on the
expense side also which has taken it
from 36.5 to 38% uh interesting play
when you split this in PSU and private
sector uh clearly psus has wors from 134
to
141 uh driven by again significant
increase in loss ratio privates from 107
to 115 so that has been the kind of a
movement that you have seen in loss
ratio uh for PSU for private sector in
particular it also in a way answers as
to what Lombard can look at it has
remained in the zone of 74.2 to 75% so
it's and there's a marginal increase in
the private sector as far as expense
ratio is conc concern we moved from
41.1% to
43.5 uh so from the balance perspective
and where I Journey can be while I don't
want to stretch the line too far we stay
committed and we do back ourselves on
two count uh one is uh in terms of the
selection that we are able to do as an
entity and secondly the manner in which
we are able to service our customer
which is at speed and in a far more
efficient manner so all of that in
Combined uh we would love to you know
probably put this across that we stay
committed to where we are uh yes at an
industry level finally we are part of a
uh overall uh you know operations of the
business uh as things stand uh we would
love to see Improvement at the industry
level also because if that happens it
can create further Niche for us and
improve our combined ratio so that's my
you know uh uh take and we stay
committed to you know take care of a
motor practice we would be agile enough
to make movements between Private Car
two wheeler and Commercial Vehicle as it
warrants at that in a dynamic manner at
any point of time uh on the second
question in terms of the stuff that we
mentioned on expense of management yes
the data is out it's there with the
regulator uh we are in no position to
put a comment we continue to pursue with
them as to what strictures they will do
at some point of time uh there are
multiple nodes and there's lot of
proactive work being done by the
regulator multiple counts including the
master circular which has come uh for
each of the product categories so we do
believe something is in the offing but
uh we are in no position to comment as
to when and how uh this would get
transpired right but you definitely
expect some action to bring the industry
in line see I from from our position we
definitely will expect but we are not
the right uh uh you know set of you know
people to comment as to how and when
they will do it that prerogative fairly
and squarely stays with them but yes we
do expect that uh some uh action will be
taken by them at some point of time so
and one more question finally on the
health segment Health segment loss
ratios have sort of wor vers in the
first half and Q2 I I know seasonally is
a little bit of a weaker quarter in that
aspect but is there any uh you know
structural problem in the industry you
know uh is pricing adequate what is your
sense so uh we continue to monitor this
closely structural problem my answer is
no are there challenges which comes on
account of some bit of seasonality which
leads to increase in frequency answer is
yes there is an element of that maduka
that does uh come in uh nevertheless uh
the way the process works and the way
the regulator has created environment if
there are challenges each one of us is
well within the rights to you know seek
a reprising of the portfolio uh so in an
agile mode all this can be addressed
over a period of
time go it sir thank you and all the
best thank you m all the best thank you
thank
you we have the next question from the
line of sankit godha from avendus spk
please go
ahead uh yeah thank you for the
opportunity um goal can you splick the
motor growth uh uh for for the quarter
and for the half into new and uh old and
and in this old can you give a bit of
color that this old is driven by the
existing customers that is they are
renewing uh what they bought last year
with you or is it the business which is
coming from other companies because
because compared to the industry we we
seems to be gain significant share of
Market um in this business so so if you
can give it color bit there and how
sustainable it is it will be useful to
to understand the future outlook too and
and the second question related to that
is that if you are doing more old in od
then ideally the loss ratio should
doriate in od but what but we are seeing
an improvement in one H or one quarter
compared to the last year so so just
wanted to understand what is playing in
our favor to to see that better loss
ratio in motori and and lastly on on PP
I believe you you guided last time that
loss of 65 to 70 is the number what you
need to watch out first and that's the
guidance you have given um and and that
was last year and now now it is start
below 65 for first half uh just just
wondering given there is no TP price
hike whether whether you believe this
number is uh still sustainable because
I'm asking this question from the
perspective that in last three years
triangles that is 23 22 21 you did not
choose to take any reserve release uh
from from from motp so so so just just
wondering whether whether this number is
sustainable or not and lastly if you can
give a data point um Health loss ratio
broken down into retail and group that's
it all right perfect super uh thanks
anit uh so one uh I think I'll take it
in the in the sequence which is the I'll
start with last and go to the first uh
so so on the breakup of the health Ross
show which is something that you
obviously ask us every quarter uh so
hence to that extent uh Quarter Two of
last year uh on the employer employee
side that number was 102% Visa that
quarter two of this year that number is
about 98 uh on the retail Indemnity
again quarter two numbers are roughly
about 66.6% and uh qu two of this year
is about
70.3 uh but again that's the point that
we have always maintained is uh I think
if you look at U on the employer
employee side largely we have said I
think the portfolio should possibly end
the year in that range of over 94 95%
this is I'm referring to the corporate
health and on the retail side I think
broadly we have talked about trying to
run the portfolio at a loss ratio around
that 70% threshold so that's why we are
kind of largely working towards at least
in so far as the portfolio buildup is
concerned uh and to your third question
on the TP uh loss ratio range that we
spoke about I think when I talked about
at an aggregate motor segment level we
had said broadly the range that we are
comfortable operating at is between 65
to
67% and within that we had said OD
possibly are looking at running between
60 to 65 and third party as you rightly
mentioned was between the range of 65 to
70 uh what we also keep saying is uh
honestly I think you should keep kind of
keep looking at numbers more on ideally
multiple annual Cycles because these are
third party books which typically runs
over multiple uh long-term periods in
terms of development and and to that
extent I think at this point of time I
think we kind of uh stay within that
range of what we spoke about which is
motor at an aggregate level of 65 to 67
and within that third party we believe
should broadly kind of run at a range of
about 65 to 70 and and and that that
also kind of resonates with one of the
other points that you rightly mentioned
which is what we are also seeing is
obviously no TP price increases and
therefore to that extent that's another
factor that we will be equ be mindful of
in terms of how we kind of res select uh
the
portfolios uh so that's in response to
question three to your point on question
two on the OD loss ratios I think I kind
of largely answered as a part of
question three which is I think the
range that you see even on a half yearly
basis or even within that uh if you look
at on Quarter Two broadly that loss
ratio range on own damage has been
running between uh in that range of
about 60 to 65 but having said that I
think uh one of the things that we have
been speaking about even in our earlier
earnings call is I think there is a lot
of thrust and focus on us to make sure
that we are able to significantly
leverage on the service parameters uh
particularly on trying to see how we can
manage the overall cost of claims in the
context of motor specifically and if you
remember one of the initiatives that we
spoke about driving in that front was to
leverage on our PPN network uh and there
again if you would have seen
uh what we have tried to do is to the
proportion of claims that has got
settled through the pp Network that
numbers have kind of uh clearly seen and
uh increase so all in all I think uh uh
pretty much comfortable with the range
at which we are operating at in the
context of own damage uh to your point
on the second one and to your first
point I did kind of give out the numbers
of the growth between new and old just
to reiterate quarter 1 new grew at about
16% old book had grown at about 33%
Quarter Two as I said the growth in new
has been largely flattish and the growth
in the renewal book has been about 26%
on a half yearly basis the growth in new
has roughly been about 7 to 8% and the
growth in the renewal book has been
close to about 30% uh 29 30% uh so
that's been the the breakup now in terms
of where is that growth largely coming
in on the old side I think as I said
there is a significant thrust on us in
terms of making sure that we we are able
to retain as many customers of ours uh
and in so far as the initiative that I
kind of also spoke about but equally
what we have also been able to see is to
also get some expanded Market as well
which is why if you see for example on
motor as a category where we used to
kind of possibly uh actually kind of see
us running at a market share of slightly
less than in fact 10% uh right now we
are at a market share of close to about
11% uh so hence in that sense um that's
also kind of aiding so obviously we have
also been accreting uh some of the
businesses from uh Market as well so
it's been a combination of both but as I
said the endeav is should try and see
how we can maximize uh retention uh
particularly at times when you see
possibly some kind of slowdown from a
market perspective then we will
obviously as I said leverage our
strengths on uh distribution service and
Technology to increase customer
retention got just a followup can you
give a trend last year one is how was
our iions and what is today in motor
just just to give a color whether it is
driven by our own book so on an average
I think what I would kind of say San is
I think if you look at it from a from a
from a motor standpoint in general and
I'm largely just kind confining to
private car and two wheeler as
categories uh on an average I would say
we would have seen an increase in
retentions ranging between 2 to 4% uh
that's the kind of uh increase in
retentions that one has seen and the
same trend line while you're talking in
the context of motor just to kind of
possibly expect a fall on on the health
side as well uh I think even there I
think what we have seen is uh obviously
a slight uptick in so far as our
retention numbers are concerned around
pretty much around the similar ranges so
I think as a as a company we believe
there's a lot that we can do in so far
as uh retaining the customers are
concerned and and to that extent is
where we are driving a lot of our
initiatives
around got thank thanks for the answer
thanks
anit thank you the next question is from
the line of additi josi from JP Morgan
please go
ahead yeah uh thank you for taking my
question and good evening uh question
you can speak a little louder that would
be great thank you so
much yeah sorry uh is it better just two
questions uh from my side uh firstly on
the investment Level side um see that
the first half investment level was
slightly downward uh so can you please
help explain like the reason behind that
and going forward what do you think of
investment leverage Trend and uh
secondly um on the uh uh retention side
premium retention it's it was slightly
On The Higher Side um so I just want to
understand your strategy uh going
forward will you plan to read in more on
your books or how are you thinking about
it yeah that's all thank you again I
will go in the in the reverse sequence
uh so uh so if you look at on the
premium retention as I said it's largely
a function of of the change in the
business mix uh as I kind of outlined at
the beginning I think in quarter 2
relatively our sourcing on the
commercial lines have been uh relatively
muted where we kind of typically have
slightly higher than EXT higher higher
reinsurance extent and therefore to that
extent retentions are lower and given
that we were cautious that book has
grown at a relatively slower Pace
compared to that I think we have seen a
significant uptake on both the retail
lines which is both retail ret Health as
well as uh our Motor Lines of businesses
both of which predominantly we end up
retaining pretty much everything on the
net account so hence to that extent is
where you would have you would have
possibly seen a slight uptick uh in so
far as the premium retentions are
concerned to your point on what can we
expect going ahead I think purely very
difficult to comment on a number because
it all depends on how we see the
momentum play out in terms of business
different lines of businesses but if you
ask us is there any change in the
thought process in terms of uh retention
versus reinsurance at this point of time
obviously there is no change in stance
but obviously we will take it as we play
through once the discussions for the
reinsurance programs happen at the
beginning of quarter 4 uh of maybe the
next calendar year beginning so that is
where we are on premium retention to
your point on investment leverage um I
think uh which is again something that
we put out as a part of the opening
transcript in the in the context of the
market being a little slow particularly
in quarter 2 uh if You' have seen as I
said industry GRE at about 133% we grew
at 20 in q1 uh Vis that market grew at
about 2% at there about in quarter 2 we
grew at roughly at about 10% So to that
extent the fact that there has been a
relative slowdown in growth that
obviously kind of acts as a factor u in
so far as uh let's say the uh investment
Leverage is concerned and secondly in
general if you would have seen the trend
line uh Q2 over q1 uh generally the the
investment Leverage seems to show a
declining Trend and this trend starts to
reverse as we kind of head into the
festive season or maybe quarter three
where you will see start seeing a lot
more collections kind of play through
and hence I think to that extent is
where we are uh on a I would say on a on
a normal trajectory I think broadly what
we should say is I think we have talked
about trying to maintain a investment
leverage of around four times I think
that's broadly the trend line that one
should expect but in a particular
quarter you can always see some of these
operations play out and also one more
thing just to add is mathematically
speaking if your growth of if your
growth of profit is higher than the
growth of investment there can be a bit
of a denominator that will come out uh
it should get moderated with cash flows
over
time sure got it thank you so much thank
you ad thank you the next question comes
from the line of nides from invest Tech
please go ahead uh thanks for the
opportunity so my question is on motor
TP in motor TP last three years there is
no price hike
and because of which the loss ratio in
the segment should ID be going up and
some of the companies I think also are
going slow in the motor TP so what is
giving us confidence that the business
that we are under iting is of
appropriate quality in terms of
profitability so NES yes there's been no
hike and I spoke about that just some
time back uh uh the configuration in
terms of how a book is placed uh the
contribution of commercial vehicle is
around 21 or you know and we always said
will remain in that range of 18 19 to 23
24% is what we expect the commercial
vehicle is which is the bare minimum we
are more driven by private car and uh
two wheeler uh so there is a mix and
selection that comes into play uh
clearly yes industry would love to see
in certain categories uh uh in trees on
the third party premium and we continue
to be in discussion with the regulator
and all the other authorities who are
involved in that uh but we stay
committed to our process of selection
and the rigor uh that which we go
through even in times when industry was
doing extremely well in certain
categories we had let go uh and had
shown a declining Trend so we have stuck
to our course and we every reason to
believe that uh we should be able to
play Play It Out The Way We have been
giving our number
that's all I can see at this point of
time simp the 60% combin loss ratio that
we are showing on motor TP is it a
function of uh decline
in decline in accident incidents or so
this number looks pretty good so why
that is how we are able to deliver this
number is it our underwriting or it is
the structural decline in uh decline in
incidents of the accidents all it is the
benefit of motor motor vehicle act that
we are getting now so the last so again
NES I I think we have kind of rated this
even in our quarter one earnings call uh
particularly on the last piece in terms
of Are We factoring in any element of uh
maybe a benefit in the context of the
likely implementation of the six-month
rule the short answer is no uh so at
this point of time we are not
necessarily factoring in anything in the
context of reserving uh at least so far
as the law of limitation is concerned
uh but if you ask us um I think so far
as third party is concerned as I keep
saying uh you should ideally start
looking at this number over longer
Cycles because of the development of the
inherent nature of the business in terms
of how the loss development takes place
and that's the reason why we said uh
generally at an aggregate level the
range that we are comfortable operating
at is between that 65 to 70% kind of a
threshold and even the point that sanjiv
made in terms of our mix of business
there if you would have seen I think uh
a large part of our third party is
significantly kind of also contributed
by the relatively higher mix that we
have on private car and two- wheelers
relative to let's say the exposures that
one has in so far as the commercial
vehicle segment is concerned so hence uh
that's also a factor that plays out and
in general I think what we have also
been able to do not just now over
periods uh I think we have been able to
significantly work on making sure that
we able to identify pockets which we
believe are viable from an underwriting
standpoint uh and and to that extent
that aids in Risk selection and if you
also remember even within CV while I
said we have been underweight I think
the call that we took if you remember
almost about four five years back is to
stay invested in the segment where we
think there is an opportunity we would
possibly take those calls in possibly
ear marking some capital on doing the
right selection and in hindsight I think
we have actually seen some of these
calls play out to our advantage so all
in all I think multiple factors that is
aiding but as I keep saying we just want
to reiterate I think the range that we
are comfortable operating is between a
65 to
70% sure and this last question on two
wheer in two wheer the seor growth has
been reasonably strong but our share of
two wheer business on a YY basis and H1
has declined from 2% 25% so what else
happening
there so that's primar the mix NES I
think again we keep saying uh it's all a
function of how you see the uh see the
uh Market play out um and and obviously
uh uh I think as things as as let's say
for example Q3 typically the cycle could
again undergo a change uh once you see
some of the demands kind of picking up
so automatically you will see the mix of
business within motor undergoing a
change uh so all in all for us there is
no specific uh there's no specific
change in thought processes unless no
I'll just this so the decline of 28 to
25 which you are referring to NES is
more the configuration uh we haven't
lost Market sh in two wheer but we we
have gained more in private car at a
faster Cliff so that changes the
percentage distribution uh of business
otherwise motor overall if you look at
it and which is a bigger number to see
we've moved from a 9.8 kind of a market
share to almost 11 which is 10.9% so
there's an overall gain and in that
Journey as the whichever way the
configuration comes out it more driven
by output of uh percentages of portfolio
distribution not that youve lost
anything in two wheer sure very thank
you thank
you thank you the next question is from
the line of jant K from Jeff please go
ahead uh thank you for the opportunity
uh just a bit on the renewal book can
you help us understand how the renewal
rates across the segments within motor
have been trended
and and how how much has improved over
the last say one or two years uh and and
maybe even the last two quarters is that
contributing uh to the renewal
growth so jant I think already kind of
possibly answered that uh I don't think
we talking specifically in the context
of uh specific Subs segments within
motor I think all that we can talk about
is to say that at an aggregate level
motor as a category we have seen an
improvement in retention broadly kind of
increasing between between 2 2 to 4% and
that's what I kind of also refer to
helping us relatively grow our grow our
proportion of the old business the
breakup of which I had given in response
to one of the questions and do you
expect this to continue improving from
here I mean Bas is the efforts that you
guys are taking on improving the the
renewals the short answer is yes J
because I think one of the other points
that I spoke about is our increased
thrust that we are putting on customer
service and if you see one of the other
things that we keep talking a lot about
which is also there in our annual report
and even in multiple of our uh of our
disclosures that we have made is clearly
at least in so far as customer
satisfaction score SL NPS scores are
concerned it is only seeing an uptick
and that automatically kind of in some
sense AIDS customers to kind of stay
hooked uh at least in so far as the
retentions are concerned so hence to
that extent that's definitely a factor
and the fact that we are also able to
divert maybe a lot of our customers in
so far as the preferred provider network
is concerned where again so far as the
customer is concerned they are assured
of uh clearly two things one obviously
it helps in so far as managing the
overall average cost of claims but two
and more importantly what we're able to
kind of assure the customer there is the
quality of repair and let's say the
relative turnaround time that we are
able to exhibit um in so far as uh
servicing those uh claims are concerned
so that is exactly what a customer looks
for when he or she
gets a claim I think the earliest
possible time within which a vehicle can
be repaired and given back that possibly
kind of results into a delightful
experience and there we have seen a
significant uptake on the PPN Network
which again is kind of translating into
an improved retention for
us thank you just thought of one last
followup on this uh in terms of channels
uh is some channel uh sort of helping
over others in terms of improving the
retention rates over
here uh
Channel wise there is uh I think again
jent
uh Channel wise see when it comes to
retaining our own customers we have our
own direct reach out to them uh to some
extent uh it's Channel agnostic uh but
yes certain categories may end up having
better retention than uh other Channel
website as a good retention agency
business is a much better retention uh
OEM relatively at times get distributed
may have a lower one but when we
approach our customers through call
center in terms of retaining it uh uh
it's more a process Improvement and a
consistent reach out that we have
created which is helping us
retain is digital slightly better over
over agency over here historically it's
been better there's no there's no doubt
on that
yes thank you very much and
congratulations on a great set of
numbers you thanks Jen thank you so much
thank you we have the next question from
the line of prish upal from ilara
Securities please go
ahead yeah hi thanks so for taking my
question um just wanted to understand
the context of the rising cat losses you
know some color in terms of how the
pricing is on the reinsurance side
specifically on the you know the cat
events how do you see that mean possibly
moving the next year or uh in the medium
term uh and um in case there is some
kind of reinsurance price he what
strategy do you think would be viable in
terms of you know at an industry level
the pass passing on of the cost or the
absorption and uh second I wanted to
understand in the health segment uh you
know what is the mix between the old and
the new book and if possibly you could
give some color on the loss ratio split
between the renewal book and the new
book uh so I think on the on the first
one um in so far as writing Rising cash
losses are concerned I think your point
is absolutely right and that is exactly
what we kind of uh keep looking for now
again if you were to slightly go back to
history uh if you remember almost about
four five years back when the market had
seen stress particularly in fire line of
business at that point of time clearly
reinsurers had stepped in and they had
said in case if companies wants to Avail
appropriate reinsurance capacity the
market has to be more disciplined in so
far as pricing is concerned and to that
extent is where they had kind of
calibrated pricing terms and the extent
of possibly reinsurance commissions that
they would be kind of ascribing to
individual companies and in that context
if You' have seen from an ICS Lombard
standpoint given that we were largely
exhibiting a profitable book in terms of
our ability to reselect better quality
book we were actually able to keep
improving our panel of reinsurers and
relatively our terms on reinsurance were
also better uh now uh and therefore now
when you look at in that country Tex if
the market further improv pricing that
is very very positive uh because that in
some sense AIDS Market to get far more
disciplined because if re insurers were
to kind of Define an increase in price
then there's a call that companies will
have to take in terms of their ability
to pass on to let's say what they're
able to do in so far as keeping it on
the net so any increase in pricing but
all this will start getting reflected
once we do our reinsurance uh
conversations which will happen towards
quarter four of this year so we will see
how that plays out uh to your point on
uh on the health side I think uh for us
the growth I think is aided by uh both
contribution by as as I said even on the
motor by I spoke about on retention even
at that point of time I had said even on
health there is a significant Focus for
us and therefore to that extent we have
also seen an improvement in the
retention ratios of customers on health
as well and in so far as the uh growth
numbers I think it is a growth that is
aided by both the retention of customers
and more importantly also if you see I
think the newly launched solution
Elevate particularly that we launched in
quarter two of this year that has been
received very well across multiple
stakeholders and that's why when you
look at retail Health as a category the
market share which was largely hovering
around 2.9% or thereabout for Quarter
Two that number stands at about 3.5%
while it's an outcome of just one
quarter as we launched this solution but
obviously I think we are quite excited
and happy with the way how this has
played out and honestly we will have to
kind of keep this momentum going as we
kind of look forward um to your point on
what could be the split in so far as the
loss ratio of new and the renewal book
is concerned honestly to my mind I think
that's purely a function of what kind of
a mix of business that we write um and
our our objective will be to obviously
write a combination of both new and
renewal and that's why I kind of talked
about in the context of the overall loss
ratio that we are comfortable on the
retail Health side which is roughly at
around 70% the mix thereof is the split
between new and renewal will be purely a
function of what mix of business that we
write okay uh so just one followup uh
you know in terms of uh the industry
loss ratios that we seeing across the
board have been rising so is that driven
more by frequency of claims or is it
also from I mean or is it just purely
claim size that has been ined uh first
frequency numbers at the industry levels
are not available so very difficult to
comment but if the loss ratio is the one
which is contributing more it can be a
contribution of nothing but frequency
and the average claim size that comes
into play is what our understanding is
yeah okay yeah thank you okay thank
you thank you ladies and gentlemen we
will take that as a last question for
today I would now like to hand the
conference over to Mr sanjie mantri for
closing comments over to you sir
yeah thank you so much for joining in I
think we're in the midst of the festive
season uh wishing wishing you all a
great Happy Diwali to you and your
family members stay good stay fit stay
happy and uh uh we are excited in terms
of what quarter 3 ands for us uh and I
hope it B it brings us all good luck
thank you so much I look forward to
interacting with you uh one to one as in
when your time permits thank you thank
you so much thanks thank
you thank you
on behalf of ICICI Lombard General
Insurance Company Limited that concludes
this conference thank you all for
joining us you may now disconnect your
lines